（ナルト）死んでたやつが
ひっかき回すな！
Dead men shouldn't go around
messing things up!
おぉ～！
（マダラ）うちは返し。
Uchiha Reflection.
（ガイ）くっ…。
I'll get the Eight and Nine Tails.
俺が八尾と九尾をやる。
Obito, you take down those two.
オビト　お前はこいつらをやれ。
なにっ　させるか！
- What?!
- You're not getting away!
（カカシ）オビト　お前に何があったんだ？
どうして　あんなやつと？
Obito...
What happened to you?
Why would you join up with him?
Summoning Jutsu!
口寄せの術！
((遅いぞ　オビト。
（ミナト）やっと来たね　キミがオビトか。
You're late, Obito!
You're finally here...
You must be Obito.
（リン）待ってたよ。
（オビト）はぁ　ギリか。
We've been waiting for you.
Barely made it...
大遅刻だよ。
You're really late.
もう自己紹介は終わっている。
あとはキミだけ。
We've already introduced ourselves.
You're the only one left!
I'm going to be the Hokage!
俺は火影になる。　うちはオビトだ。
My name's Obito Uchiha!
んでもって　俺の火影岩には
トレードマークのゴーグルと→
For my Great Stone Face,
make sure my trademark goggles
and Sharingan are nicely carved out!
更に
写輪眼もしっかり彫ってもらう。
それで他里に
にらみをきかせてやんのだ！
So I can glare over
the neighboring lands!
はぁ。
（オビト）写輪眼でメンチきってる→
I'll scare the hell out of them
with my Sharingan stare...
俺の火影岩にビビって
ここには手を出さねえようにな。
and no one will dare
attack our village!
そんなのは火影になって
写輪眼を開眼してから注文しろ。
Rattle off your instructions
after you become the Hokage
and activate your Sharingan.
だいたいゴーグルしてたら
写輪眼は彫れないだろ。
Besides, how can they carve
the Sharingan
if you're wearing goggles?
（オビト）ゴーグルの上から彫れば
いいだろうが！
They can carve it out
over my goggles!
それだと目が飛び出てる
みたいになるね。　フフッ。
Then it will look like your eyeballs
are popping out.
とにかく　俺と同じ夢を持ってる
部下ができて嬉しいよ。
Anyway...I'm happy that
someone on this team
shares my dream.
今日からキミの上司になるミナトだ。
よろしく。
I'm Minato. From today,
I'll be your superior.
I'm glad to meet you!
(おぅ！))
Yeah!
Minato Sensei...
《オビト：ミナト先生。
もう　こんなとこは…。
All of this...
こんな世界は…》
This world...
《オビト：どうでもいいんだよ！》
- None of it matters anymore!
んなわけにいくか　ボケ！
I'm not gonna let
that happen, idiot!
I'm the son of
the Fourth Hokage, you know!
俺ってば　四代目火影の息子だぞ。
てめえの口車なんかにはのらねえ。
I'm not gonna fall for your talk!
そうか。
人柱力の本体だからと→
I see.
I was going easy on you
because you were
the actual Jinchuriki, not a clone.
大目に見てやったが…
なら　手加減はできんぞ。
but if that's how you feel,
I won't hold back on you!
かつて　俺の九尾を縛り上げた
柱間の木龍だ。
This is Hashirama's wooden dragon,
which he used to hold down
my Nine Tails long ago.
（キラービー）
やっぱマダラは　ムチャクチャ強ぇな。
Madara really is crazy powerful.
それこそ
やりがいがあるというもの。
That's what makes him
worth fighting.
Your tough guy act is crazy solid.
あんたは　強がりが強ぇな。
こっちだって
ゾンビ相手に手加減はしねえ。
I'm not going to hold back
against a zombie either!
死んでんだからな。
Since you're already dead!
なぜだ？
なぜ　マダラのようなやつと。
Why?!
Why ally yourself with someone
like Madara?
（オビト）お前に
語るべきことなど何もない。
I've got nothing to say to you.
All that's left...
あるのは　この…　最終決戦だけだ。
is this final battle!
Kakashi's Resolve
土遁　土流壁！
Earth Style...
Mud Wall!
ウッ。
な　なぜだ。
もう口を閉じたらどうだ。
Why?
How about shutting up already?
You're only talk.
You're nothing but a piece of trash.
口先だけのクズは。
グハッ。
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero.
((俺は白い牙を
本当の英雄だと思ってる。
確かに　忍の世界で→
Sure, in the world of Ninja,
one who breaks
the rules and regulations
ルールや掟を破るやつは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
is regarded as trash.
But those who abandon
their comrades...
けどな→
仲間を大切にしないやつは
それ以上のクズだ。
are worse than trash!
This is probably...
(お前が　リンを…
見殺しにしたからだろうな))
because you let Rin die.
（カカシ）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
I am trash for sure...
《確かに　俺はクズだ。
だが　オビト　お前はずっと…》
But Obito, you've always...
神威！
Kamui...
...been my hero.
《俺にとって英雄だった。
どうして…》
So why?
グッ…　この！
Damn it!
That damned wooden thing!
あの木の野郎
九尾のチャクラを吸ってやがる！
It's absorbing
the Nine Tails' chakra!
クッソ…！
Damn it...
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ。
同じ眼だ。　やはり出てきたか。
We have the same eyes...
So you made it out, huh?
Obito, how did you end up like this?
オビト　なぜ　そうなった。
リンが　関係してるのか？
Does it have to do with Rin?
うっ。
((仲間は　俺が守る))
I'll protect my comrades!
((すぐにリンを助けに行くぞ))
Let's go rescue Rin right now!
((おい))
Yeah!
うわっ。
I said, trash should keep
their mouths shut!
クズは　口を閉じていろと
言ったはずだ。
死ね。
Die.
俺は　お前との約束を
守れなかった。
I...couldn't keep
my promise to you.
You're right. I'm trash.
そう　俺は　クズだ。
But you...
だが　お前は　木ノ葉の英雄だ。
You're a hero of the Leaf.
お前まで
そうなる必要はないだろ。
There's no reason for you
to become trash too.
あっ…。
クッ　ハハハッ　ハハハッ　これが現実だ。
This is reality.
託した側も　託された側も→
Those who bequeath
and the bequeathed...both.
この世界で生きながらえた忍は
皆　クズになる。
All shinobi who survive
in this world become trash.
俺たちが　いい例だ　カカシ。
You and I are prime examples,
Kakashi.
《カカシ先生》
Kakashi Sensei...
（八尾）うっ　動けねえ。
I can't move...
These guys are a distraction
for you too, right?
こいつらは　お前も邪魔だろう？
もうじき　この世界も終わる。
This world is about
to come to an end.
しばしの間　２人で楽しむために→
So in order to enjoy
the little time we've got left...
Let's clear out this battlefield first.
まず　戦場を
整理しておくとしよう。
No one can escape the cycle
that gives birth to trash in this world.
この世界のクズを生む輪からは→
皆　逃れることはできない。
だから　俺は
この世界をつくり変える。
That's why I intend
to remake the world!
おめえら　ムカつきすぎて→
You guys make me so mad,
I can't even think straight.
文句が思いつかねえ。
だから　かわりに
俺のことを　ひとつ教えておく。
So instead, let me tell you
something about myself.
俺は　クズじゃねえ。
I'm not trash!
この先　クズにもならねえ。
I'm not planning on
becoming trash either!
I will...
俺は　させねえ。
stop you!
俺の仲間は　絶対　殺させやしねえ。
- I'll never let my comrades die!
((俺の仲間は
絶対　殺させやしないよ))
I'll never let my comrades die!
I'm sorry, Naruto.
《カカシ：すまん　ナルト。
オビトの言葉を教えた俺が→
I'm the one who taught you
Obito's words, and yet...
また　ブレるところだった》
I was about to waver again.
（ガイ）昼虎。
Hirudora!
雷切。
Lightning Blade!
強がりじゃなかったな。
Guess it wasn't just a bluff.
（カカシ）オビト　かつての
お前の意志は　今でも→
Obito...
Your once strong will
is still alive today...
俺の隣にいる。
今の俺にできることは→
Right next to me!
What the current me can do
is protect the current Naruto!
今のナルトを守ることだ！
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
今のナルトを守る？
You'll protect the current Naruto?
俺も　同じくな。
Same here...
《キラービー：限界のくせしやがって。
They're both at their limits!
木ノ葉は　どいつも
強がりばっかだな》
These Hidden Leaf guys
sure love to act tough!
ん…。
木の縛りが弱まったぜ。
The wood's constriction
is weakening.
ビーのおっちゃん！
Octopops!
いてっ！　いて…。
Ow oww!
気ぃつけろ　ナルト！
敵の木遁縛りは→
Be careful, Naruto!
The enemy's Wood Paralysis is identical
to the First Hokage's!
初代　火影のと同じだ。
尾獣の力を縛る力があるぜ。
It has the power to
bind Tailed Beast Power!
ヤマト隊長のと一緒か。
Like Captain Yamato's technique...
（オビト）写輪眼　頼みの雷切→
A Lightning Blade that relies
on the Sharingan...
ずいぶん左眼を使いこなすように
なったな。
You've mastered your left eye...
万華鏡まで。
Even awakening the Mangekyo.
だが　もう一度
時空間から戻ってこれるか？
But can you make it back
from the other plane
その状態で。
in your current condition?
うっ　く…。
クズかごに入ってろ！　カカシ！
Go back to the trash heap, Kakashi!
カカシ先生も…。
Kakashi Sensei...
俺と一緒だ！
is just like...me!
そろそろ　十尾のほうも
やべえな。
Looks like we're gonna have to
start worrying about Ten Tails.
オビトってのは　あっちに任せんだ。
Let them handle Obito.
その隙に　こっちもやるぜ！
Then we'll make our move!
ヘッ！　今度は　はっきりわかんぜ。
Now I see it clearly...
てめえの苦しがるツラがよ。
your pained face.
（オビト）そんなセリフは　隣のやつを見て
言ったらどうだ？
Save those lines for
the one right next to you.
ハァ　ハァ…。
《確かに　カカシ先生を
なんとかしねえと。
I definitely have to help
Kakashi Sensei somehow.
写輪眼の使いすぎで
バッテバテになってるし→
He's completely drained from
overusing the Sharingan.
もう　吸い込まれたら…》
If he gets sucked in...
（九喇嘛）ナルト　少し代われ。
Naruto, switch with me...
え？
ここは　わしにやらせろ。
Huh?
Let me handle this.
でも…。
いいから代われ！
But...
Don't argue. Just switch!
（九喇嘛）おい　カカシのガキ　手ぇ出せ。
Hey, Kakashi brat,
give me your hands...
お前は…。
You're...
（九喇嘛）いいから　早く手ぇ出せ！
Never mind that!
Just stick out your hands!
うわぁ　アホ！　九喇嘛！
なんてことしてんだよ！
Kurama! What the heck
did you just do?
これで気がねなくやれる。
Now you don't have any distractions.
あとは任せたぞ　ナルト。
I'm leaving the rest to you, Naruto.
はぁ！？
What?!
くっそ！！
Damn!
能力がわかってる分→
Now that we know how
your ability works, I can counter it.
注意してれば反撃できる。
更に　もう１発！
Here's another!
ああ
確かに苦しそうなツラだな　オビト。
Oh yeah, that certainly
is a pained face Obito.
何だ！？
What's going on?
向こうのカカシがやったんだ。
Kakashi did that. Over there.
お前と　わしの違いはな→
The difference between
you and me is...
チャクラの受け渡しが
自由にできるってことだ。
I can give
またあとで
お前にもコツを教えてやる。
いつ渡したの？
カカシをぶん投げようと
手をつかんだときだ。
じゃあ…。
もちろん。
いつでも　神威で出てこられる。
カカシ先生！
（カカシ）九尾に礼を言っといてくれ。
あぁ！
復活する前に　チリヂリに吹き飛ばす！
ありったけ　ためろ！
おう。
もう行けっぜ！
ビーのおっちゃんに　八っつぁん。
よし！　うて！！
これで　終わりだ！！
魔像のチャクラが…　消えた！
やった！
やったんだよ。
バカヤロー　このヤロー！
よっしゃあ～！！
終わった…　のか？
ああ…　この世界がな。
さてと…。
始めるか…。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手の
皆さんによる→
華麗なステージを
お届けいたします。